(Transcrito por TurboScribe.ai. Atualize para Ilimitado para remover esta mensagem.) I'll leave you off with a beautiful story
that happened to one of the great rabbis
of our generation, Agaon Rav Shteynman, Zecher et
Tzaddik V'Kadosh L'Bedacham.
I'm sure many of you have heard about
the great Tzaddik, if not even all of
you.
I was in Israel when he passed away.
It was right before Hanukkah.
Such an unbelievable Tzaddik.
The power, his warmth.
I'm sure many of you might have even
been Zocher to be by the rabbi.
And something amazing happened, that one time the
rabbi was in America.
In one of his unbelievable holy avodot that
he was doing.
And unfortunately he wasn't feeling well.
So they had to fly him back to
Israel.
They're not putting the rabbi on no Boeing
747, not even first class.
They chartered the rabbi a private jet.
He got a philanthropist from Canada and he
flew the rabbi back on a private jet.
So the rabbi is going on the private
jet.
And the jet could hold up to 10
people.
Being that the rabbi is from Bnei Brak,
they fit 20.
So the rabbi is going on the plane.
He's sitting over there.
Tzaddikim, they're not going with the rabbi.
They're not leaving the rabbi.
So he's on the plane.
And the plane takes off.
And the head steward comes over to the
rabbi in the middle of the flight.
And he says, I understand that the rabbi
is the VIP of the flight.
All of this is just for you.
So I'm going to be your head steward
for the flight.
Anything you need, we can get you on
this plane.
But anything, we can get you on this
flight.
Kalim 25, Shaburma, anything that you might need,
anything, you can probably get on the flight.
Is there anything that we can get you?
So he starts thinking.
And the Hasidim are confused.
Rabbi, you're thinking?
At home, you barely eat a small piece
of bread and a little butter.
On the plane with this goyim, you're thinking
what you need on the flight.
They're confused.
So he says, give me 10 minutes, let
me think of something.
Okay?
10 minutes later, the steward comes back to
the rabbi, and he says, Rabbi, what can
we get you?
So the rabbi says, you said you can
do anything, right?
Anything you need, Rabbi, please tell us, we'll
have you on the plane.
Anything I need?
Anything.
He says, well, you see, we pray three
times a day.
Jews.
The morning prayer, afternoon, and evening prayer.
One, I was able to make before the
flight.
The third, I'll be able to pray in
Israel.
But the second, I'm going to have to
pray on the plane.
I don't like praying on the plane, my
concentration.
Could you please land the plane?
Are you kidding?
Where?
In the middle of nowhere?
Land the plane?
What do you want?
He said he was doing it.
I'm just asking.
Okay, he goes to the cockpit.
A few minutes later, the captain gets on
the MC.
Gentlemen, please take your seat.
We're getting ready for landing.
In the middle of nowhere.
I don't know where they landed.
He landed the plane.
Rabbi got off with his minyan.
He prays.
He gets back on the plane.
And he takes off.
Unbelievable.
Rabbi, come on.
What are you doing?
Do you understand what tefillah is?
Why would I miss one?
We could pray on the plane.
But it won't be the same.
Every tefillah is priceless.
And Burei Olam loves us.
He's given us the opportunity to pray whenever
we like.
24-7, 365.
He gives us his undivided attention.
All we have to do is tap into
this unbelievable and beautiful kovach called tefillah.
To work more on my tefillah.
Amen, amen.
Everybody, thank you for coming.
And have a wonderful Rosh Chodes Tov.
You've just experienced another Torah class brought to
you by TorahAnytime.com